Finding aid to Celebrations and Conferences Files CA.MS.00083
Smith College Archives
Celebrations and Conferences Files
1922-2007
Smith College Archives
Smith College.
CA.MS.00083
1.458 linear feet (5 containers)
Records deal with issues such as race, class, sex, art, famous persons, history, and politics. Materials include photographs, newspaper clippings, pamphlets, publications, conference notes and reports, press releases, and speeches. Of particular note are the extensive records documenting the conference, Campuses Against Racist Violence.
Biographical / Historical
Smith College has hosted a large number of celebrations and conferences. Converging upon the campus, many of the participants were Smith students, students from various colleges, Smith alumnae, guests, and guest speakers invited by the college.
Scope and Contents
The files contain photographs, newspaper articles from local papers reporting on the event, and various pamphlets and publications from the events themselves. Many of the folders have only a newspaper clipping while others contain only photographs. However, a few of the files contain conference notes and reports, photographs, press releases, programs, and speeches.
Many of the conferences deal with issues such as race, class and sex in addition to history and politics. The various celebrations that are included also address history and politics in addition to art and famous persons.
Information found in the Campuses Against Racist Violence box is much more complete. Taking place in 1991, the conference records contain both event planning and event documents. Also included are documents from the event, however, there are no records of the event's success.
The folders are arranged alphabetically.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials in the Smith College Archives are open for use, with the following exceptions: "Office Files," files of records created for the use of the administrative unit that created them, are closed to research for a period of 10 years following their creation.
In all cases, the College Archives will continue to provide public access to materials that were intended to be public at the time of their creation (press releases, publications, etc.)
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Source unknown.
Congresses and conventions--Massachusetts--Northampton.; Smith College.
- American Presidency Conference, 1989 (Box 68)
- American Presidency Conference Conference, 2001 (Box 68)
- Berkshire Conference, 1984 (Box 68)
- "Breaking Barriers: The Struggle for a Latina Identity", 1993 (Box 68)
- Conventions of Gender, 1984 (Box 68)
- Diversity, Multiculturalism, and Political Correctness at Universities, Conference, 1993 (Box 68)
- "Education at the Grassroots: Women and the Struggle for a Safe Environment, 1995 (Box 68)
- Eighteenth Century Conference, 1947 (Box 68)
- Ethics in Medicine and Science, 1982 (Box 68)
- "Future of Feminism" Conference, 1993 (Box 68)
- Gender, Authority and Leadership: Perspectives from the Political World, 1990 (Box 68)
- Gender in Hip Hop Music and Culture, 2000 (Box 68)
- Ghandi Centennial Celebration, 1969 (Box 68)
- Interterm Conference: China Today, 1990 (Box 68)
- International Association of Physical Education and Sport for Girls and Women, 1999 (Box 68)
- Japan-America Student Conference, 1998 (Box 68)
- Model League of Nations, 1933 (Box 68)
- Model League of Nations Photographs, 1933 (Box 68)
- Moliere Tercentenary Celebration, 1922 (Box 68)
- New England Black Students Conference, 1994 (Box 68)
- New England Renaissance Conference, 1964 (Box 68)
- Of Women Born: The Rebirth of Midwifery in 20th Century America, 1999 (Box 68)
- Renaissance Conference, 1953-1976 (Box 68)
- Kathleen Ridder Conference, 1991 (Box 68)
- Ronsard Celebration Photographs, 1926-1927 (Box 68)
- Safe Schools, 2000 (Box 68)
- Simon S Shargo Memorial Conference, 1983 (Box 68)
- Southern New England, 1942 (Box 68)
- Transgender Conference, 2000 (Box 68)
- United Nations and Photographs, 1946-1949 (Box 68)
- "What's Next" American Pluralism and the Civic Culture, 1999 (Box 68)
- Woman's Health: The Impact of Physical Activity and Nutrition, 1994 (Box 68)
- Women, Welfare and Higher Education: Public Policy Continued, undated (Box 68)
- Campuses against Racist Violence (CARV) Conference, 1991 (Box 68.1)
  Biographical / Historical
  The Campuses Against Racist Violence Conference was a college-wide function that aimed to create awareness of and possible solutions for acceptance. It was a two night and one day conference with workshops and group discussions specifically aimed at college campuses and students.
  - Committees (Box 68.1)
  - Financial (Box 68.1)
  - Food (Box 68.1)
  - General (Box 68.1)
  - Memorabilia (Box 68.1)
  - Organization and Planning (Box 68.1)
  - Reading Lists (Box 68.1)
  - Registration (Box 68.1)
  - Special Needs (Box 68.1)
- Conference - "Preserving Women's History: Archivists and Historians Working Together" - tapes of sessions, May 30-31, 1984 (Box 68.2)
- Conference - "Preserving Women's History: Archivists and Historians Working Together" - photographs, May 30-31, 1984 (Box 68.3)
- Power of Women's Voices Conference, 2007 (Box 3)